batchgeocode.com 2014-11-01

# Protect your map information | BatchGeo

Using BatchGeo your map data stays on your own computer unless you choose to save it using the "Continue / Save" option. If you save the map your information will be sent to our servers and stored in a secure database.

When saving the map you will be given the option to keep the map unlisted or make it available publicly. If you choose to keep it unlisted, a random and unguessable URL will be created using a 128 bit 32 character hash. This URL will not be published on our web site, it will not be indexed by Google. The only way this URL will be found by public search engines is if you choose to publish it on a public site.

The URL really is impossible to guess, in fact in the 128 bit hash there are 309,485,009,821,345,068,724,781,056 possible values. 

If you use the "Public" option when creating your map we may choose to feature your map or link it in our examples section. You can change the Public / Private option at any time using the edit screen.

Anonymized information from your map may be made available to Google so as to enable advertising. To opt out of this you will need to subscribe to our Pro version.

Our Pro version by default includes the security features of the free version, and has the following additional features:

  * Information is always transferred between the client and our servers using encrypted protocols ([SSL](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Secure_Sockets_Layer)).
  * You have the option of making your map password protected or only shared amongst BatchGeo users you explicity grant permissions.*
  * Your map data will not be shared with advertisers.
  * Individual addresses will be sent to Google for purposes of Geocoding, they will be sent over [SSL](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Secure_Sockets_Layer) and decoupled from other data you upload to BatchGeo.

* BatchGeo support staff may access your map in order to troubleshoot issues at your request. Staff may also at random check map data to ensure that no terms of use have been broken (such as using map for illegal purposes) and that BatchGeo services are working as intended. BatchGeo staff will access only in a secure environment using encrypted data transmission and complex passwords.

BatchGeo uses the best and most secure cloud platforms. Our servers are routinely patched and kept up to date with the most secure versions of required software. Passwords are kept in a salted and hashed format (never in clear text.) Your data will be stored securely in a database that is kept behind a firewall and not directly accessible from the Internet. We periodically conduct site wide scans and engage in external security audits.

### Information we collect and how we use it

We may collect the following types of information: 

  * **Information you provide** – When you sign up for a BatchGeo Account, we ask you for personal information. We may combine the information you submit under your account with information from other BatchGeo services or third parties in order to provide you with a better experience and to improve the quality of our services. For certain services, we may give you the opportunity to opt out of combining such information.
  * **Cookies** – When you visit BatchGeo, we send one or more [cookies](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTTP_cookie) to your computer or other device. We use cookies to improve the quality of our service, including for storing user preferences, improving search results and ad selection, and tracking user trends, such as how people search. BatchGeo also uses cookies in its advertising services to help advertisers and publishers serve and manage ads across the web and on BatchGeo services.
  * **Log information** – When you access BatchGeo services via a browser, application or other client our servers automatically record certain information. These server logs may include information such as your web request, your interaction with a service, Internet Protocol address, browser type, browser language, the date and time of your request and one or more cookies that may uniquely identify your browser or your account.
  * **User communications** – When you send email or other communications to BatchGeo, we may retain those communications in order to process your inquiries, respond to your requests and improve our services. When you send and receive SMS messages to or from one of our services that provides SMS functionality, we may collect and maintain information associated with those messages, such as the phone number, the wireless carrier associated with the phone number, the content of the message, and the date and time of the transaction. We may use your email address to communicate with you about our services.
  * **Location data** – BatchGeo offers location-enabled services that will attempt to offer enhanced features based on your location. If you use those services, BatchGeo may receive information about your actual location (such as GPS signals sent by a mobile device) or information that can be used to approximate a location (such as a cell ID).

In addition to the above, we may use the information we collect to: 

    * Provide, maintain, protect, and improve our services (including advertising services) and develop new services; and
    * Protect the rights or property of BatchGeo or our users.

If we use this information in a manner different than the purpose for which it was collected, then we will ask for your consent prior to such use.

BatchGeo processes personal information on our servers in the United States of America and in other countries. In some cases, we process personal information outside your own country.

### Choices

Most browsers are initially set up to accept cookies, but you can reset your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, some BatchGeo features and services may not function properly if your cookies are disabled.

Unless you are using the Pro version of our software, BatchGeo uses the [DoubleClick advertising cookie](http://www.doubleclick.com/privacy/dart_adserving.aspx) on AdSense partner sites and certain BatchGeo services to help advertisers and publishers serve and manage ads across the web.

### Information sharing

BatchGeo only shares personal information with other companies or individuals outside of BatchGeo in the following limited circumstances:

    * We have your consent. We require opt-in consent for the sharing of any sensitive personal information.
    * We provide such information to our subsidiaries, affiliated companies or other trusted businesses or persons for the purpose of processing personal information on our behalf. We require that these parties agree to process such information based on our instructions and in compliance with this Privacy Policy and any other appropriate confidentiality and security measures.
    * We have a good faith belief that access, use, preservation or disclosure of such information is reasonably necessary to (a) satisfy any applicable law, regulation, legal process or enforceable governmental request, (b) enforce applicable Terms of Service, including investigation of potential violations thereof, (c) detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security or technical issues, or (d) protect against harm to the rights, property or safety of BatchGeo, its users or the public as required or permitted by law.

If BatchGeo becomes involved in a merger, acquisition, or any form of sale of some or all of its assets, we will ensure the confidentiality of any personal information involved in such transactions and provide notice before personal information is transferred and becomes subject to a different privacy policy.

### Information security

We take appropriate security measures to protect against unauthorized access to or unauthorized alteration, disclosure or destruction of data. These include internal reviews of our data collection, storage and processing practices and security measures, including appropriate encryption and physical security measures to guard against unauthorized access to systems where we store personal data.

We restrict access to personal information to BatchGeo employees, contractors and agents who need to know that information in order to process it on our behalf. These individuals are bound by confidentiality obligations and may be subject to discipline, including termination and criminal prosecution, if they fail to meet these obligations.

### Accessing and updating personal information

When you use BatchGeo services, we make good faith efforts to provide you with access to your personal information and either to correct this data if it is inaccurate or to delete such data at your request if it is not otherwise required to be retained by law or for legitimate business purposes. We ask individual users to identify themselves and the information requested to be accessed, corrected or removed before processing such requests, and we may decline to process requests that are unreasonably repetitive or systematic, require disproportionate technical effort, jeopardize the privacy of others, or would be extremely impractical (for instance, requests concerning information residing on backup tapes), or for which access is not otherwise required. In any case where we provide information access and correction, we perform this service free of charge, except if doing so would require a disproportionate effort. Because of the way we maintain certain services, after you delete your information, residual copies may take a period of time before they are deleted from our active servers and may remain in our backup systems. Please review the service Help Centers for more information.

### Enforcement

BatchGeo adheres to the US Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of Notice, Choice, Onward Transfer, Security, Data Integrity, Access and Enforcement.

BatchGeo regularly reviews its compliance with this Privacy Policy. When we receive formal written complaints, it is BatchGeo’s policy to contact the complaining user regarding his or her concerns. We will cooperate with the appropriate regulatory authorities, including local data protection authorities, to resolve any complaints regarding the transfer of personal data that cannot be resolved between BatchGeo and an individual.
